<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dæmon1024</title>
    <link>https://daemon1024.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on dæmon1024</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://daemon1024.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Whatsapp . . </title>
      <link>https://daemon1024.github.io/posts/leaving-whatsapp-.-.-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daemon1024.github.io/posts/leaving-whatsapp-.-.-/</guid>
      <description>The reasons seems to be obvious, the new privacy policy.
Am I also part of the herd? Is it because everyone seems to be moving to it? Na I have been using signal for quite a time now but I mostly used it for saving notes to self, since nobody else seemed to use it. Even if you are trying it out just because Elon Musk tweeted &amp;ldquo;Use Signal&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;s fine, Signal is worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File Descriptors and Resource Usage Limits</title>
      <link>https://daemon1024.github.io/posts/file-descriptors-and-resource-usage-limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daemon1024.github.io/posts/file-descriptors-and-resource-usage-limits/</guid>
      <description>Backstory I was working on a project in go where I had to open and play around with too many files at once ( around 50 thousand ). The program ran fine when I was working with one file at a time. But when I tried to make it concurrent, I had an error saying Too many open files.
Now that&amp;rsquo;s weird cause my hardware wasn&amp;rsquo;t the bottleneck, I had enough free ram, my CPU wasn&amp;rsquo;t maxed out and I had plenty of empty storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Shell commands and How do they execute?</title>
      <link>https://daemon1024.github.io/posts/basic-shell-commands-and-how-do-they-execute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daemon1024.github.io/posts/basic-shell-commands-and-how-do-they-execute/</guid>
      <description>Shell A shell is a command line interface for a UNIX-like operating system. A UNIX system offers a variety of shell types like
 sh or Bourne Shell bash or Bourne Again shell : It is the standard GNU shell used commonly by Linux users. csh or C Shell ksh or Korn Shell and many more . .  You can see what shell are available in your system by running cat /etc/shell</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free vs Open-Source Software</title>
      <link>https://daemon1024.github.io/posts/free-vs-open-source-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daemon1024.github.io/posts/free-vs-open-source-software/</guid>
      <description>Softwares are a integral part of our lifestyle right now. Some of them are proprietary and some of them are not. The one&amp;rsquo;s which are not proprietary are generally associated with FOSS i.e. Free and Open Source Software. Let&amp;rsquo;s dig a bit deeper into the non proprietary world.
What is FOSS? FOSS i.e Free and Open Source Software, is any piece of software that is freely licenced to use,study,copy and modify and the source-code is openly shared so that people are encouraged to voluntarily contribute to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://daemon1024.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daemon1024.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, I&amp;rsquo;m Barun. I am a undergraduate student working on some cool open-source projects.
If you want to check some of my stuff out then you can do that! at Github Profile
You&amp;rsquo;re always free to reach out to me at my email address: barun1024@gmail.com
You can also contact me through Telegram or Matrix.
I feel very passionate about helping people out where possible and doing small things to make other peoples lives easier and more fun!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
